(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-05T08:40:28.130322",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
はずむこころ！
Bouncing heart!
とぶようなテンション！
Soaring with excitement!
さあコネクトしよ！
Now let's connect!
I Mean... No More Hiding
Changing... So I'm Trying Now
あれ？ いまこう思って、言って、
Huh? Thinking like this, and saying...
ああそうじゃなくて…
Ah, no, that's not it...
ええとあの歌はなんだっけ？
Um, what was that song again?
どうするんだっけ？
What was I supposed to do?
しっちゃめちゃっちゃThinking
Muddled, messy thinking,
ぐるぐるNow Loading…
spinning, now loading...
[Ctrl]+[Z]効かないし
Ctrl+Z doesn't work,
複雑カスタマイズ
complex customization.
足りない？何か
Something's missing?
インストールとかできたらな
If I could just install it...
なんて不完全で
How imperfect,
なんて不確実で
how uncertain,
答えはどこだって
where is the answer?
説明書なんてないよね
There's no manual, right?
まずは始めてみようかな…
First, shall I try beginning?
違う姿 違う形
Different looks, different forms,
なにもして 同じ気持ち！
yet why do we share the exact same feeling!
繋がってる実感
The sensation of being connected,
分け合うぬくもり ありがとう
sharing warmth, thank you.
思いっきり伝えたいんだ
I want to convey it with all my might,
からふる！笑顔！心地いいな♪
colorful! Smiles! It feels so good♪
繋がっていくみんなと ここが私の好きな場所
Connecting with everyone, this is my favorite place.
はずむこころ！
Bouncing heart!
とぶようなテンション！
Soaring with excitement!
今コネクトしよ！
Now let's connect!
I Mean... No More Hiding
Changing... So I'm Trying Now
きっと頑張ってみたって 変われないって
Even if I try my best, I can't change,
諦めてトライしてみるって
giving up and trying anyway,
前段階にして
making it a preliminary step.
部屋でぼっちcrying
Crying alone in my room,
ネガティブばっかmy mind
my mind is all negative.
思ったようになくって ボッキリ折れてたって
Things didn't go as planned, my heart shattered,
ココロもう一度 踊らせていきたいんだ
but I want to make my heart dance once again.
いいよ不完全で いいっだっていいっだって
It's okay to be imperfect, any way is fine!
もう隠さないんだ 理想へ届かなくても
I won't hide anymore, even if I can't reach my ideal.
いいよ一歩 踏み出してみようかな…
It's okay, maybe I'll take a step forward...
違うイロが 違う夢で 進むミライ
Different colors, different dreams, the future we walk towards
きっとステキ！ 見えないけど感じる
must be wonderful! Even if unseen, I can feel it.
あったか優しさ ありがとう 思いっきり歌いたいんだ
Warm kindness, thank you, I want to sing with all my might!
ハピフル！笑顔！届けたいな♪
Happyful! Smiles! I want to deliver them♪
出会っていくオリジナリティ みんなとの大切な場所
Discovering originality, this precious place with everyone.
ヒトリでカンペキじゃなくていいんだ みんなと一緒にgoing
It's okay not to be perfect alone, going together with everyone.
私にできること 見つけてくから ah
Finding what I can do, ah...
違う姿 違う形 なのに本物だ！
Different looks, different forms, yet it's the real thing!
同じ気持ち！ 繋がってる実感
The exact same feeling! The sensation of being connected.
分け合うぬくもり ありがとう 思いっきり伝えたいんだ
Sharing warmth, thank you, I want to convey it with all my might!
カラフル！笑顔！心地いいね♪
Colorful! Smiles! It feels so good♪
繋がっていくみんなと ここが私の好きな場所
Connecting with everyone, this is my favorite place.
はずむこころ！ とぶようなテンション！
Bouncing heart! Soaring with excitement!
さあコネクトしよう！
Now let's connect!
見つけていくから
I'll keep looking for you...
Ah
違うカタチ違う形なとに
Though our shapes are different,
本当におんなじ気持ち
we share the exact same feelings!
繋がってる時間
The time we spend connected...
分け合う温もりありがとう
Thank you for sharing your warmth with me!
思いっきり伝えたいんだ
I want to express it with all my heart!
カラフル笑顔がちょうどいいね
A colorful smile is just right!
繋がってくみんなと
Connecting with everyone...
ここが私の好きな場所
That is my favorite place!
弾む心と高鳴るテンション
Let's make our hearts beat fast with high tension!
さあ Connect しよ！
So let's connect!
I Mean... No More Hiding...
Changing... So I'm Trying Now...
踊れオーケストラ
Odore Orchestra
作詞・作曲：YASUHIRO(康寛)
Music & Lyrics by YASUHIRO (Yasuhisa)
さあさあこの指に止まれ
Stop right there at the tip of your finger!
後悔後でしたって知らないぞ
Even if you regret it later, you won't know!
音にのまれて
Get swept away by the sound,
歌って踊って満たすだけ
sing, dance, and just fill it all up!
ぱんぱん手を打ち鳴らして
Clap your hands and ring them out!
そらそら示しどんな足音も
Listen closely to every unique footprint!
鳴らし出して今導き出すよ
Tune it up and guide the way right now!
正体は実は案外痒いもの
The truth is actually quite simple:
魔法のタクト空にかざすだけ
just hold up a magic baton to the sky!
おいでよ
Come on!
街を包み込んだ超常現象が
A surreal phenomenon wrapping up the town!
夜空にほらこだまして退屈が泣き出すよ
Echoing endlessly across the night sky,
孤独な愛を運命よ
lonely love is destiny,
最終もソテーキの音が
leaving the final notes behind!
君は聞こえた？
Did you hear it?
星に舞う旋律を
A melody dancing among the stars!
ワン・ツー・サン・シで泣いてた
1, 2, 3, 4, crying out loud,
過去に負けない巡る力を
letting go of the spinning power that never loses!
たった楽しいリズムで途切れない音乗せて・ととん
Set it all to a fun, unbreakable rhythm!
忘れてた景色の中のその向こう
I forgot about the scenery beyond that horizon!
未定調和のほころびモノクロの望遠鏡
Unsettled joy, monochrome binoculars...
待った無しのぶっつけ本番で
Once again, no waiting around for the main stage!
奏でよう理想輝く幻想的真紅で
Play it loud, making ideals shine bright!
いつも目が合うあいつと手を繋ぎ踊ろう
Whenever our eyes meet, we hold hands and dance!
何度泣いて泣いた心のエレジーを
How many times have I cried my heart out?
僕は聞こえた、だから今ここにいるんだ
I heard it too, and that's why I'm here right now!
正体は実は案外悲しいもの
The truth is actually quite simple:
魔法の音色空に響かせて
just echoing magical colors across the sky!
街を包み込んだ超常現象が
A surreal phenomenon wrapping up the town!
夜空にほらこだまして退屈が泣き出すよ
Echoing endlessly across the night sky,
愉快な歌を歌おう最終演奏アンサンブルを
a delightful song to play till the end!
君は聞こえた？
Did you hear it?
星に舞う旋律を
A melody dancing among the stars!
ワン・ツー・サン・シで泣いてた
1, 2, 3, 4, crying out loud,
過去に負けない巡る力をタッタ楽しい
letting go of the spinning power that never loses!
テンポも寝付けない音を乗せて
With a lively beat and restless sounds playing on...
パンパン手を打ち鳴らせ
Clap your hands and make some noise,
踊れ踊れオーケストラ
dance, dance, orchestra!
バイバイ今夜はさよなら
Bye-bye, goodnight for tonight,
次は君もステージで
next time you'll be on stage too!
さあさこの指に止まれ
Now come on, catch my finger,
後悔後でしても知らないぞ
don't say I didn't warn you if you regret it later.
耳をすまして
Listen closely
僕らと踊るだけ
and just dance with us.
これでいいいなのだ　好好好
All's a-ok-o, ha-ha-hao!
好きの需要と供給の寒暖差
Love's supply and demand fluctuate wildly,
また風邪びきさん
catching a cold once again.
忍ぶ修行は効率が肝心だ
Efficiency is the key to ninja training,
ぼくはわかってるもん
I know that well enough!
でも簡単じゃないね 簡単じゃないの
But it ain't easy, no, it just ain't easy.
心の乙女があれこれ言っちゃうの
My inner maiden blurts out all sorts of things,
雲問題がだいね 頑張ってドクター
a massive problem, help me out, doctor!
感情が爆散 頭あちな
Emotions explode, my head's on fire!
好好好のラブ連単
Ha-ha-hao of a love trifecta!
きみとしたいことがいっぱい
There are so many things I want to do with you,
いつも「足んないな」ってなる問題
yet the eternal problem is "still not enough."
欲張り星人のせいなんで
It's all because I'm a greedy space alien!
ううもう嫌い嫌い嫌い嫌い大嫌いとか思ってみたい
Ugh, I wanna try thinking "I hate you so much!"
でも好好好のラブ連単 “愛したほうが勝ち”なんだって
But ha-ha-hao, "the one who loves more wins"!
これでいいいなのだ　好好好
All's a-ok-o, ha-ha-hao!
ところがローな脳がお目覚めだ
But then my low-energy brain wakes up,
bad駄々っ子ぱーりないもうだめだ
bad bratty party night, I'm done for!
誰にでも嫉妬しちゃって胸が取れそう
Jealous of everyone, my heart's about to burst.
最高セット こっち向いて
Best set, look over here!
最低セット あっち向いて
Worst set, look over there!
感情は日替わり ヘい テンションチャンプルー
Emotions change daily, hey, a tension champuru!
また押っ雪かないね 押っ雪かないの
Gotta push again, don't you see?
あたしが重すぎて揺れない恋シーソー
This love seesaw won't budge, I'm too clingy!
雲問題がだいね 頑張ってドクター
A massive problem, help me out, doctor!
残念が爆散 頭あちな
Disappointment explodes, my head's on fire!
好好好のラブ連単
Ha-ha-hao of a love trifecta!
気持ち抑え込んでいった
I hold my feelings deep inside,
きみが「足んないな」ってなるような
making you feel like you want more.
大人バランスがいいんだって
Adult balance is what's needed,
忙しいだなんてうっそー ごめん寝てたなんてうっそー
"I'm so busy," psych! "Sorry, I was sleeping," psych!
迷走しちゃうあたし 安らかに死ねばいいのに
I'm so lost, I might as well rest in peace!
好好好のラブ連単
Ha-ha-hao of a love trifecta!
これでいいいなのだ
Is this all a-ok-o?
頭あちな
My head's on fire!
好好好のラブ連単
Ha-ha-hao of a love trifecta!
きみのしたいこともちょうだい
Give me whatever you want to do too!
刺激バッキュンビーム打ち放題
Fire off thrilling laser beams all you want.
欲張り星人にになっちゃいよ
Why not become a greedy alien?
大嫌い嫌い嫌い嫌い嫌い大嫌いとか思っちゃうのやだ
I hate you so much... No, I hate thinking that!
好好好のラブ連単 愛されちゃん欲しがっています
Ha-ha-hao, this cherished girl is craving love!
へっちゃらピーポーイタさも逆にオッケー はっちゃけピーポーダサさも逆にオッケー ぶっちゃけピーポーウザさも逆にオッケー 言ったらいいじゃんせーので
Easy-peasy peeps, cringe is totally fine! Wild peeps, lame is totally fine! Real talk peeps, annoying is totally fine! Just say it together, ready, set—
これでいいいなのだ　好好好
All's a-ok-o, ha-ha-hao!
はい！皆さん！百鬼あやめ生誕祭2024にお越しくださり、ありがとうございます！やったー！
Yes! Everyone, thank you so much for attending Nakiri Ayame's Birthday Fest 2024! Yay!
と改めまして、えほりらいぶ2024の百鬼あやめです！ありがとみんな来てくれて、ほんとにありがとね！
Once again, I am Nakiri Ayame from Ehori Live 2024! Thank you all so much for coming!
え、今回のね、配信なんですけど、え、右上にありますこちら！え、ハッシュタグ、え、シャープ百鬼あやめ生誕祭2024で、あのスクショやらね、感想やらをぜひたくさんポストしてくれると、う、が嬉しいです！ぜひぜひ、しゅしゅしゅとポストしてください皆さん！よろしくね！
For today's stream, please check out the hashtag in the top right: #NakiriAyameBirthday2024! Please post lots of screenshots and thoughts, I'd be so happy! Post away, everyone!
ということでですね、みなさん、ちょっとお気づきになられましたでしょうか？ここまでの、え、繋がるコネクト、踊れオーケストラ、ハオ、この曲やっていくなかでみなさん、うんこ！？
So, everyone, did you happen to notice something? While going through connected songs like "Odore Orchestra" and "Hao," did you notice... poop?!
うんこ！？あれ？うんこ！？今なんて言ったの？みたいなの、あれ、傷を負われましたかね？
"Poop?!" Huh? "Poop?!" What did I just say? Did that catch you off guard or something?
あ、そうです！そうです！こちらで！そのね、階段演出を今回初めてやらせていただいたんですけど、みんな気づいたかな？
Ah, exactly! Right here! We did a staircase entrance production for the first time this time, did everyone notice?
このね、でっかいこの、このパネルから、あのゲストのみんなやら、う、がね、こう降りて、こ、こ、ね、へへへへ
From this huge panel right here, all the guests and everyone came walking down... hehehe!
えへへ、みたいな感じをやらせていただいてたんですけど
I was trying to do something like that, but
え、すごいでしょう？
Eh, isn't it amazing?
ほらね、扉も開くんです よ、この
Look, the doors open too, this...
おっ、ほら！すごい！そう、これこれこれこれ！ありがとうございます！このね、その、光ってるところからみんなが出てくるんですけれども
Oh, look! Amazing! Everyone comes out from that glowing spot, but
そしてね、ちょっとステージの紹介もしていこうかなと思うんですけど、ちょ、ちょ、あそこのちょ、ちょっと、あ、し、閉めるか。
And, I thought I'd introduce the stage too, but wait, over there, close it.
おい！あ、ちょっとちょっと、ちょっと！はーい！
Hey! Ah, wait, wait, wait! Yay!
ということでですね、今回のライブのね、ステージちょっとすごい、いろんな 形が来てくれてます。見て！
So for this live, the stage is pretty amazing, various shapes have come. Look!
このまずね、ちょっとこのね、動物たちをちょっと見ていただこうかな。
First, let's look at these animals.
見えるかな？あ、ね、可愛いでしょう？猫ちゃんやらね、 熊さんやら、あの、たくさ、うさ、うさちゃんやらね、
Can you see? Right, aren't they cute? Cats, bears, and lots of bunnies,
こうたくさん動物がごステージ上で踊ってくれてます！
lots of animals are dancing on the stage!
そして、えい、気付いたかな？
And, hey, did you notice?
このポヨヨもね、見て！この今回のライブのコンセプトの仕様に合わせて ポヨヨもね、楽器を持ってくれてたり、なんか帽子をね、お帽子かぶってくれてます（笑）。可愛い！
This poyoyo too, look! In accordance with the concept of this live, poyoyo is holding instruments, and wearing a hat. Cute!
いや、可愛い！はい、ということで、
So cute! Yeah, so,
今回のライブのステージはですね、コンセプトは、えー、みんなね、こう夢のような楽しい時間も過ごしてほしいなということで、
the stage for this live's concept is, um, for everyone to spend a dreamy, fun time like this, so
ちょっとパレードっぽいようなお祭りみたいな、ちょっと賑やかな感じに、え、可愛く、明るい感じに させていただきました！
kind of like a parade or festival, in a lively, cute, bright way, I was allowed to do it!
ね、今回のライブを通して、みんながね、楽しい気持ちになってくれたら嬉しいなと思っております。
Right, through this live, I hope everyone gets into a fun mood.
で、この先もね、あの、え、こんなこと歌って踊るのみたいな、初めて、あのね、出てくれるゲストの方やらもいらっしゃいますので、ぜひこの先も楽しんでいただければと思います。
And from here on too, there are first-time guest appearances coming out, so I hope you enjoy from here on too.
この先も、見てってねー！
Please keep watching ahead!
どうしたら あなたに愛を刻めるんだろう?
How can I carve my love into you?
知らない気持ちばかり覚えたよ
I've only learned unfamiliar feelings
忘れかたも教えて
Teach me how to forget too
言葉だけじゃなくてさ 震える指の温度から
Not just with words, from the warmth of trembling fingers
それは誰の希望? 私からあふれ出した願いの雫
Whose hope is that? A tear of prayer overflowing from me
消えても消えても 生まれてくるけど
Even if it vanishes, it's born again, but
答えなき酷い未来 何回目の明日が来るのか
A cruel future with no answers, how many tomorrows will come?
わからない夜なら 名前を呼ばれたい
If it's a night I don't know, I want my name called
だって胸が痛い 痛くて張り裂けそうだ
Because my chest hurts, hurts so much it's about to burst
どうしたら あなたに愛を刻めるんだろう?
How can I carve my love into you?
私がいつか空に溶け消える前に
Before I eventually melt away into the sky
強い想いですべてを守りたかった理由は あなたをもっと見ていたから...
The reason I wanted to protect everything with strong feelings was because I wanted to see you more...
程良い笑顔なんていらないよ 甘い嘘で隠した
I don't need a moderate smile, hidden by sweet lies
傷を分かちあえたら 嘆き飲み込む意味がある
If we can share our wounds, there is meaning in swallowing our sighs
そして夢に変わり あなたへと伝えたい誓いの雫
And changing into a dream, a tear of vow I want to tell you
叶わない叶わない 気づいてるけどね
Even though I realize it won't come true
捧げるんだ 祈りを
I offer up this prayer
永遠じゃない存在でも 確かな光を欲しがる危うい命だよ
Even as a transient being, it's a fragile life desiring a sure light
もっと一緒にいてよ 世界が壊れても
Stay with me longer, even if the world breaks
いつだって こころは愛を止められない
Always, the heart cannot stop love
あなたはいつも何を探しているの?
What are you always searching for?
暗い闇へと 今は向かうべきだけれど
Now I should head into the dark darkness, but
それまであなたを側で見つめていよう
Until then, let me gaze at you by your side
もしも、と問いかけて 声は風のなか小さくなっていく
Asking "what if?", my voice grows faint in the wind
すべてを話してよ そっと抱きしめてあげたいよ
Tell me everything, I want to gently hold you
なのに流れる時間が示すのは すれ違いながら遠ざかる二人
Yet time flowing shows two people passing and drifting apart
どうしたら あなたに愛を刻めるのか?
How can I carve my love into you?
いつだって こころは愛を止められない
Always, the heart cannot stop love
あなたはいつも何を探しているの?
What are you always searching for?
強い想いですべてを守りたかった理由は あなたをもっと見ていたくて ああ空に溶け消えるまでは...
The reason I wanted to protect everything with strong feelings was because I wanted to see you more... until I melt away into the sky...
程良い笑顔なんていらないよ 甘い嘘で隠した
I don't need a moderate smile, hidden by sweet lies
傷を分かちあえたら 嘆き飲み込む意味がある
If we can share our wounds, there is meaning in swallowing our sighs
そして夢に変わり あなたへと伝えたい誓いの雫
And changing into a dream, a tear of vow I want to tell you
叶わない叶わない 気づいてるけどね
Even though I realize it won't come true
捧げるんだ 祈りを
I offer up this prayer
永遠じゃない存在でも 確かな光を欲しがる危うい命だよ
Even as a transient being, it's a fragile life desiring a sure light
もっと一緒にいてよ 世界が壊れても
Stay with me longer, even if the world breaks
いつだって こころは愛を止められない
Always, the heart cannot stop love
あなたはいつも何を探しているの?
What are you always searching for?
暗い闇へと 今は向かうべきだけれど
Now I should head into the dark darkness, but
それまであなたを側で見つめていよう
Until then, let me gaze at you by your side
もしも、と問いかけて 声は風のなか小さくなっていく
Asking "what if?", my voice grows faint in the wind
すべてを話してよ そっと抱きしめてあげたいよ
Tell me everything, I want to gently hold you
なのに流れる時間が示すのは すれ違いながら遠ざかる二人
Yet time flowing shows two people passing and drifting apart
どうしたら あなたに愛を刻めるのか?
How can I carve my love into you?
いつだって こころは愛を止められない
Always, the heart cannot stop love
あなたはいつも何を探しているの?
What are you always searching for?
強い想いですべてを守りたかった理由は あなたをもっと見ていたくて ああ空に溶け消えるまでは...
The reason I wanted to protect everything with strong feelings was because I wanted to see you more... until I melt away into the sky...
どうしたら あなたに愛を刻めるんだろう?
How can I carve my love into you?
知らない気持ちばかり覚えたよ
I've only learned feelings I never knew.
忘れかたも教えて
Teach me how to forget, too.
言葉だけじゃなくてさ 震える指の温度から
Not just with words, from the warmth of trembling fingers...
それは誰の希望?
Whose hope is that?
私からあふれ出した願いの雫(DROP)
A drop of desire overflowing from within me.
消えても 消えても 生まれてくるけれど
Even if it vanishes, even if it vanishes, it's born anew.
答えなき酷い未来
A cruel future with no answers.
何回目の明日が来るのか わからない夜なら 名前を呼ばれたい
On a night when I don't know how many tomorrows await, I want you to call my name.
だって胸が痛い 痛くて張り裂けそうだから
Because my chest hurts, hurts so much it feels like it's going to tear apart.
どうしたら あなたに愛を刻めるんだろう?
How can I carve my love into you?
私がいつか空に溶け消える前に
Before I eventually dissolve and fade into the sky,
強い想いでいまを守りたかった理由は
the reason I wanted to protect the present with strong feelings...
あなたをもっと見ていたくて ah
is because I wanted to keep watching you, ah...
程良い笑顔なんていらないよ
I don't need a moderate smile.
甘い嘘で隠した
Hidden behind sweet lies.
傷を分かち合えたら 嘆き飲み込む意味がある
If we can share our scars, there's a point to swallowing our sighs.
そして夢に変われ
And turn it into a dream.
あなたへと伝えたい誓いの雫(DROP)
A drop of vow I want to convey to you.
叶わない 叶わない 気付いてる
It won't come true, won't come true, I know that.
だけどね捧げるんだ祈りを
Even so, I offer up this prayer.
永遠じゃない存在でも
Even as a fleeting existence,
確かな光を欲しがる危うい運命だよ
it's a perilous fate craving a definite light.
もっと一緒にいてよ 世界が壊れても
Stay together with me more, even if the world breaks apart.
いつだって こころは愛を止められない
Always, my heart cannot stop its love.
あなたはいつも何を探しているの?
What are you always searching for?
暗い闇へと 今は向かうべきだけれど
We should be heading into the dark abyss now, but...
それまであなたを側で見つめていよう
until then, let me watch over you by your side.
流れ星空へと打ち返す
Shooting stars strike back into the sky.
ドナドナ絶句のオートマリィ
Donadona speechless automatics.
ホームラン かぐや姫が叫ぶ
Homerun, Princess Kaguya cries out.
九回裏のストーリー
Bottom of the ninth story!
驚いたUFOが落ちてく
A startled UFO is falling down.
やりすぎ愛・アイ・アム・ソーリー
Overdoing it, I am sorry.
目が覚めてティーチャーが微笑んだ
Waking up, the teacher smiled.
絶対絶命・命!
Desperate situation, life!
充電がフルになるまで
Until the charge is full,
あと少し夢見みたいな
just a little more, it feels like a dream.
胸の中 ウサギとカメがずっと競争している
In our hearts, the hare and the tortoise are always competing.
ドンと来いだよ
Bring it on!
ハンデ有りのノンフィクション
A non-fiction with a handicap.
この瞬間がスタート切るチャンスなんだ
This very moment is the chance to start!
ドンと来いだよ
Bring it on!
気合入れてこんちくしょう
Put your spirit into it, dammit!
もうあっという間 大学生しちゃうもんね
It's already in the blink of an eye, acting like college students, huh?
飛べ飛べもうちょいだけ高く 行け行けもうちょいだけ遠く
Fly higher, jump just a bit higher; go further, go just a bit further.
君と私本気だせば 限界なんてちょいの一ちょいと
If you and I give it our all, limits are just a little something...
破じゃん 1000%テンペスト
Break through, 1000% tempest!
お弁当 海の玉手箱や
Bento box, the sea's treasure chest.
それなら 宝石箱や
If not that, a jewel box.
どんぶりコース ざっと流れてこい
Donburi course, flow right on in.
桃でもケーキでもいいな
Peaches or cake are fine, too.
食べ過ぎてまぶたが落ちてく
Eating too much, my eyelids are falling.
相撲で勝負だ水物
It's a showdown of sumo, water things.
目が覚めてティーチャーが微笑んだ 残りね!
Waking up, the teacher smiled. There's some left!
世界中巻き込みながら 好きなだけ遊びたいなあ 楽しさが一番!
Involving the whole world, I just want to play as much as I like! Fun is number one!
100年後 100万年後には 昔話に乗っけてよ
A hundred years later, a million years later, put it into an old tale.
ドン詰まりっ子 無敵になるモチベーション
Stuck in a tight spot, motivation becomes invincible.
来た来た来たこの感覚が また頑張る合図なんだ
Coming, coming, this feeling is the signal to try hard again!
ドン詰まりっ子 笑顔見せてなんのその
Stuck in a tight spot, show a smile and what of it?
まだまだまだまだ あれこんなもんだっけ?
Still, still, still... wait, was it really like this?
大逆転しちゃうもんね
We're gonna pull off a massive turnaround!
飛べ 飛べ
Fly, fly,
もうちょっとで届く
we'll reach it in just a bit!
行け 行け
Go, go,
もうちょっとで変わる
it'll change in just a bit!
君と私一緒だったんだ
You and I were together all along.
心配なんてなくなくないと
There's nothing to worry about at all!
小さい気にしません
Don't sweat the small stuff!
質問！あなたが鬼退治を任されたらどう戦いますか？
Question! If you were tasked with subduing the demons, how would you fight?
リアー！
Roar!
鬼ヶ島に遊園地と温泉とサウナを作って、毒気を抜いて平和的解決を図ります！
I'd build an amusement park, hot springs, and a sauna on Onigashima to disarm them and pursue a peaceful resolution!
でもね たまに赤点取る
But you know, sometimes we fail
日もあるよ
our tests too.
そううちら人間なんだもん
That's right, we're only human after all!
なんたもん なんたもん
After all, after all!
さあお団子食べて行きますか
Now then, shall we go eat some dango?
諦めるなんてことは絶対にないよ
Giving up is something that will never happen!
ドンと来いだよ ハンディ有りのノンフィクション
Bring it on! A non-fiction story with handicaps.
今今この瞬間がスタート切るチャンスなんだ
Right now is our chance to make a fresh start!
ドンと来いだよ 気合入れてこんちくしょう
Bring it on! Let's pump ourselves up, dammit!
ほらほらほらもうあっちゅうま大逆転しちゃうもんね
Look, look, look! Before you know it, we'll pull off a massive turnaround!
飛べ 飛べ もうちょいだけ高く
Fly, fly, a little bit higher!
行け 行け もうちょいだけ遠く
Go, go, a little bit further!
君と私
You and me
本気出せば限界なんてちょちょいのちょいね
If we go all out, limits are a piece of cake!
フレフレ私たちへ フレフレみんなへ
Cheer for us, cheer for everyone!
フレフレ！インフレだって強く生きましょう
Cheer up! Even with inflation, let's live strong!
フレフレ私たちへ フレフレみんなへ
Cheer for us, cheer for everyone!
フレフレ！フレンドシップ見せてやるぞ
Cheer up! We'll show you our friendship!
ドン！パチャイ1000% とっとと止まらん行け行け！
Bam! 1000% vibes! Keep on going without stopping, go go!
きゅるりーんしてみて？
Can you try making cute puppy eyes?
定義不能の感情登場
Undefined emotions appear.
わんちゃんねこちゃんに持つそれとは違うだってあの子はそうつまり
It's different from what you feel for dogs or cats—meaning that girl is, well...
まさかとうそれをできちゃうでしょって嫌なやつは私
And I'm the obnoxious one who thinks, "Could she actually pull that off?"
万事不毛のお気持ち論争
A totally futile emotional debate—
人間誰しもが持つ微妙なところだって私もだけどさ
the subtle flaws everyone has. Well, I have them too, but...
まさかもっとわかりやすくねやってみようか
Shall we try making it a bit easier to understand?
だけど、そのためには誰誰誰かのひいきがいる お願い、そっちからってことにして
But for that, we need someone's favoritism. Please, let's pretend it came from your end!
わからなくなってきた結局一番いいのはねねどっち？
I'm getting confused. In the end, which is best, hey, which one?
君の「きゅるりーん」してみてって言葉だけで伝えたい恋も吹っ飛んじゃうくらい気にするのは君のことだけでいいんだね
Just hearing you say "Can you make cute puppy eyes?" blows away my feelings—I guess I only need to worry about you.
ねぇ、「きゅるりーん」って言葉だけでここまで全部が正解なんだって思えちゃうのはちょっと反則じゃん
Hey, thinking that just the word "kyururin" makes everything right is kind of cheating, isn't it?
最大級の最大級の最大級の最大級の恋なんですだって君の顔が言ってる
It's the most maximum, ultimate crush—your face is telling me so!
最大級の最大級の最大級の最大級のきゅるりーん、してみて？ね
Can you give me your most maximum "kyururin"? Hey?
比較不要のそういう環境 この子もその子もどの子も悪くないけど
In an environment where comparison is unnecessary, this girl, that girl, every girl is fine, but...
だってあの子は昨日より今日の方が五割増しでしょ
That girl is 50% cuter today than she was yesterday, right?
みんなに会える、だけど、その前にさ、誰誰誰かの頑張りもいる
We get to see everyone, but before that, someone's hard work is also needed.
わかった、その分優しくも知ってわかるまで考えよ
I get it, I'll be gentle in return and think until I understand.
結局みんながいいのはねねどっち？
In the end, which one does everyone prefer, hey, which one?
君の「かわいい」してみてって相づちだけでわかんないけれど可愛い気がしてる気がするならとりあえずそれでいいんだね
Just your response of "Can you look cute?"—I don't quite get it, but if it feels cute, I guess that's fine for now.
「かわいい」って疑問系で聞いてみるのもなんかつまらないでしょ
Asking "Am I cute?" as a question is kind of boring, isn't it?
根拠のない自信もみんなにちょうだい
Give everyone some groundless confidence too!
君の「きゅるりーん」してみてって言葉だけで伝えたい恋も吹っ飛んじゃうくらい気にするのは君のことだけでいいんだね
Just hearing you say "Can you make cute puppy eyes?" blows away my feelings—I guess I only need to worry about you.
ねぇ、「きゅるりーん」って言葉だけでここまで全部が正解なんだって思えちゃうのはちょっと反則じゃん
Hey, thinking that just the word "kyururin" makes everything right is kind of cheating, isn't it?
「はぁ…♡」
"Ah..." ♡
2-2-2-2 (きゅきゅきゅきゅる)
2-2-2-2 (kyu kyu kyu kyuru)
2-2-2-2 (どぅんどぅんどぅんどぅん)
2-2-2-2 (doom doom doom doom)
2-2-2-2 (きゅきゅきゅきゅる)
2-2-2-2 (kyu kyu kyu kyuru)
2-2-2-2 (ずんずんずんずん)
2-2-2-2 (zoom zoom zoom zoom)
2-2-2-2 (きゅきゅきゅきゅる)
2-2-2-2 (kyu kyu kyu kyuru)
2-2-2-2 (ばんばんばんばん)
2-2-2-2 (burn burn burn burn)
(ちゅちゅちゅ)
(chu chu chu)
open your karte♡
Open your karte ♡
救助不可能 (darling)
Incurable (darling)
恋の病なのは (dirty)
A sickness of love (dirty)
どんどん熱を上げていく virus (love me)
A virus raising the fever higher and higher (love me)
危険な治療 (twinkle)
A dangerous treatment (twinkle)
試してみる？ (blink)
Want to try it? (blink)
飽きるまで天使の優等生 (heaven in hell)
An angel's honor student till you get bored (heaven in hell)
ドキドキ動機は純粋
A pounding mechanism is pure heart
曖昧乙女心
An ambiguous maiden's heart
どっちどっち
Doki-doki, dochi-dochi
さあ手の平の迷宮へようこそ
Now, welcome to the labyrinth in the palm of your hand
「いい子だね♡」
"Good job ♡"
カルテNo. 運命の2222
Karte No. Fateful 2222
鳴り止まないサイレン音が
The unceasing silent sound is
wee woo wee woo
好き？好き？速まる愛的心電図
Like it? Like it? The speeding ECG of love
はいお薬をどうぞ♡
Here, please take your medicine ♡
to to to u ♡
きゅるりーんしてきて
Kyuru-in, try doing it
ヒトリゴトだよ
It's just a monologue
恥ずかしいこと聞かないでよね
Don't listen to embarrassing things
キミのことだよ
It's about you
でもその先は言わないけどね
But I won't say what comes after that
掛け違えてる
Muddled up
ボタンみたいなもどかしさを
Like buttons that are hard to fix
ほどけないまま
Leaving them untied
また難しくしようとしてる
Making it difficult once again
伝えたい気持ちは今日も
The feelings I want to tell you are, even today,
言葉になる直前に 変換ミスの連続で
Right before becoming words, with a series of typos,
ため息と一緒に飲み込んだら
If I swallow them down along with a sigh,
ほろ苦い…
They taste so bittersweet...
ふとしたときに探しているよ
I'm searching for them when I least expect it
君の笑顔を探しているよ
I'm searching for your smile
無意識の中 その理由は
In the back of my mind, the reason
まだ言えないけど
Is still something I can't say
ひとりでいると会いたくなるよ
Whenever I'm alone, I start wanting to see you
誰といたって会いたくなるよ
No matter who I'm with, I start wanting to see you
たった一言 ねぇどうして あぁ…
Just a single word, hey, why is it... Ah...
言えないその言葉 言えないこの気持ち あぁ…
I can't say those words, I can't say this feeling, ah...
早く気づいてほしいのに
I wish you would notice already...
千ピースある パズルみたいな選択肢と
A thousand-piece puzzle of choices
想像力が 判断力の邪魔をしちゃう
My imagination gets in the way of my judgment
つかめない気持ちは今日も
The feelings I can't grasp are, even today,
可愛くない顔みせて 自己嫌悪+後悔を加えて
Showing an uncute face, mixing self-hatred and regret,
ため込んだ「ごめんね」を吐きだすには ほど遠い…
Spitting out the apologies I've bottled up is still a long way off...
耳を澄ませば聞こえてくるよ 君の声だけ聞こえてくるよ
If I lend an ear, I can hear it, I can hear just your voice
雑踏の中 気づかないふりをしているけど
Pretending not to notice amidst the hustle and bustle,
隣にいると嬉しくなるよ 近くにいると寂しくなるよ
Being next to you makes me happy, being far makes me lonely
単純なことでもどうして あぁ…
Such a simple thing, yet why is it... Ah...
言えないその言葉 言えないこの気持ち あぁ…
I can't say those words, I can't say this feeling, ah...
もっと素直になりたい
I want to be more honest...
泣き出しそうな空模様…
A sky that looks like it's about to cry...
頬に一粒 雨かな…
A single drop on my cheek, is it rain...?
不安定な心 傘で隠した
I hid my unstable heart under my umbrella
ヒトリゴトに全部隠した
I hid it all away as a monologue
ほんとはずっと あぁ…
I've truly always felt this way, ah...
ふとしたときに探しているよ
I'm searching for them when I least expect it
君の笑顔を探しているよ
I're searching for your smile
無意識の中 その理由は
In the back of my mind, the reason
まだ言えないけど
Is still something I can't say
ひとりでいると会いたくなるよ
Whenever I'm alone, I start wanting to see you
誰といたって会いたくなるよ
No matter who I'm with, I start wanting to see you
たった一言 ねぇどうして あぁ…
Just a single word, hey, why is it... Ah...
言えないその言葉 言えないこの気持ち あぁ…
I can't say those words, I can't say this feeling, ah...
早く気づいてほしいのに
I wish you would notice already...
さぁみんな 始まるよー！
"Everyone, it's starting!"
ワン ツー スリー はい！ それそれそれそれ！
"One, two, three, ready! Sore, sore, sore, sore!"
うれしくって はしゃいじゃって どどーんどうーん
"So happy, getting so excited, boom, boom!"
ゆらゆらっと ひらひらっと はなまうゆかた
"Swaying and fluttering in a flower-dancing yukata"
髪を結って 帯を巻いて ぎゅぎゅぎゅーんっ！
"Tie up my hair, wrap my sash, tight, tight, tight!"
まだまだやぐらは 始まったばかり！
"The yagura festival has only just begun!"
もう一回！
"One more time!"
まだまだよ！
"Not yet!"
もう一回！
"One more time!"
とどけとどけ 想いよとどけ
"Reach, reach, let my feelings reach!"
追えば逃げて ぐるぐる回る
"Chase it and it runs, spinning round and round"
目指すは一等賞！ 目指すはぶっちぎり！ おそるる ことなかれー！
"Aiming for first place! Aiming to leave them in the dust! Have no fear!"
どどどどどすの？どうすの！？
"What's with the booming? What do we do!?"
レッツゴー！！
"Let's go!!"
めっちゃめちゃ めっちゃめちゃ よいさよいさ よいさよいさ
"Super super super super, yoisayoisaya!"
踊り踊り狂え
"Dance, dance and go wild!"
トレセン音頭で よーよいの よーい！
"To the Toresen Ondo, yo-yoi no yoi!"
めっちゃめちゃ めっちゃめちゃ あいやいさ あいやいさ
"Super super super super, aiyaisa, aiyaisa!"
踊り踊り狂え
"Dance, dance and go wild!"
めっちゃめちゃ めっちゃめちゃ あいやいさ あいやいさ
"Super super super super, aiyaisa, aiyaisa!"
トレセン音頭で よーよいの よーい！
"To the Toresen Ondo, yo-yoi no yoi!"
歌いすぎて 息が苦しい！
"Singing too much, I'm out of breath!"
酸素だ！ 酸素だ！ 酸素を持ってこーい！！
"Oxygen! Oxygen! Bring me some oxygen!!"
まんまんまんまん… ばーちゃっかー！！
"Man-man-man-man... Ba-chakkar!!"
とまらん… とまへん！
"Can't stop... Won't stop!"
ぎーりきりっとー
"With sharp, crisp steps"
やーる気でてきた そう！！
"I'm getting motivated now!!"
あれ？ 誰もやってなーい！
"Huh? Nobody else is doing it!"
こよい星がまたたいて… って言ってるばいかーい！！
"Tonight the stars are twinkling... wait, that's what I'm saying!!"
どどどどどすの？どうすの！？
"What's with the booming? What do we do!?"
レッツゴー！！
"Let's go!!"
めっちゃめちゃ めっちゃめちゃ よいさよいさ よいさよいさ
"Super super super super, yoisayoisaya!"
踊り踊り狂え
"Dance, dance and go wild!"
めっちゃめちゃ めっちゃめちゃ よいさよいさ よいさよいさ
"Super super super super, yoisayoisaya!"
トレセン音頭で よーよいの よーい！
"To the Toresen Ondo, yo-yoi no yoi!"
めっちゃめちゃ めっちゃめちゃ あいやいさ あいやいさ
"Super super super super, aiyaisa, aiyaisa!"
踊り踊り狂え
"Dance, dance and go wild!"
めっちゃめちゃ めっちゃめちゃ あいやいさ あいやいさ
"Super super super super, aiyaisa, aiyaisa!"
トレセン音頭で よーよいの よーい！
"To the Toresen Ondo, yo-yoi no yoi!"
遥か彼方の銀河から 君に届け スペースオペラ！
"From a distant galaxy, reaching you: Space Opera!"
ハイ！
"Ready!"
ガラクタで作った スペースシップ
"A spaceship made of junk"
あふれそうなハートごとのせて
"Carrying a heart that's about to overflow"
君のシグナル 探索中 いまだ！この星をとぶのだ！
"Searching for your signal—now's the time to fly across this planet!"
チェック チェック！ 進路だいじょうぶ？
"Check, check! Is our course okay?"
行けば進路になるからだいじょうぶ！
"Wherever we go becomes the path, so it's okay!"
さあジャック ジャック 電波ジャックだ！
"Now, jack, jack, a radio wave jack!"
あっ！君の受信アンテナ
"Ah! Your receiving antenna"
やっと出逢えたね どこにいても見つけるよ
"We finally met! No matter where you are, I'll find you."
振れた気持ちを 歌に乗せて この宇宙すべてにわんごほーい！
"Put your trembling feelings into a song and shout it out to the whole universe!"
オ！ペ！ラ！スペースオペラ！ 君に！届いてアリシア！
"O-pe-ra! Space Opera! Reaching out to you, Alicia!"
想いが（ハイ！）
"My feelings (Ready!)"
愛が（ハイ！） 壮大すぎて伝えきれない
"and love are too grand to fully convey"
オ！ペ！ラ！それでもいいや その笑顔も涙も不器用な愛情も全部乗せて
"O-pe-ra! Even so, it's fine. Loading up your smiles, tears, and clumsy affection!"
さあラタタタタタタラッタ 歌えるトゥトゥトゥトゥトゥトゥルゥトゥ
"Now, ratatata, sing along, tu-tu-tu-tu-turutu!"
小さな星からみれば悲劇も 宇宙からみれば喜劇だ！いえい！
"Viewed from a small star, it's a tragedy; viewed from space, it's a comedy! Yeah!"
さあラタタタタタタラッタ 歌えるトゥトゥトゥトゥトゥトゥルゥトゥ
"Now, ratatata, sing along, tu-tu-tu-tu-turutu!"
遥か彼方から辿り着きおした 君に届けスペースオペラ！ (ハイ！)
"Arriving from far away, reaching you: Space Opera! (Ready!)"
重なる周波数 繋ぐ電波（でんぱ！） 聞かせて君のカデンツァ（カデンツァ！）
"Overlapping frequencies, connected radio waves! Let me hear your cadence!"
輝く点と点が夜空で合体！
"Dots and points resonating and uniting in the night sky!"
ぷくせんふえかくせいざ ずっと探してた
"Constellations drawn on staves, I've been searching for them all this time."
また歌が生まれる意味を キモチなんてわかんないまま歌う ララララララ
"Singing without even understanding the meaning of why songs are born, la-la-la-la-la..."
それが遠く届き響きあったとき この歌に 君が意味を 与えたんだ！ この宇宙やっぱりわんごほーい！
"When it echoes far and wide, you gave meaning to this song! This universe is truly wonderful!"
遥か彼方の銀河から
From a distant galaxy
君に届け スペースオペラ!
Reach you, space opera!
ガラクタで作った スペースシップ
A spaceship made of junk
あふれそうなハートごと 載せて
Loaded with overflowing heart
君のシグナル 探索中
Searching for your signal
いまだ!この惑星をとぶのだ!
Now! Fly to this planet!
チェック チェック!進路だいじょうぶ?
Check check! Is the course okay?
行けば進路になるからだいじょうぶ!
If I go, it'll become the course!
さあ ジャック ジャック! 電波ジャックだ!
Come on, jack jack! Radio wave jack!
あった!君の受信アンテナ
Found it! Your receiving antenna
やっと 出逢えたね どこにいても見つけるよ
Finally met you, no matter where
振れた 気持ち歌に載せて
Shaking feelings put into song
この宇宙すべてに わんどほーい!
To all of this universe, wander-hoi!
オ!ペ!ラ!スペースオペラ!君に!届いてアリア
O! Pe! Ra! Space opera! To you!
想いが ラブが 壮大すぎて 伝えきれない
Thoughts and love are so grand
その笑顔も 涙も
That smile and tears too
不器用な愛情も ぜんぶ乗せて
Clumsy affection as well, load it all up!
歌え ルツツツツツツツ ツルッツツ
Sing, lutututututututu trultu!
小さな星からみれば悲劇も
From a small star, tragedy
宇宙からみれば喜劇だ!いぇいいぇい!
Looks like comedy from the universe! Yay!
歌え ルツツツツツツツ ツルッツツ
Sing, lutututututututu trultu!
遥か彼方で恋をした
Fell in love far away
君に届け スペースオペラ!
Reach you, space opera!
かさなる周波 つなぐ電波
Overlapping frequencies connecting radio waves
きかせて君の カデンツァ
Let me hear your cadenza
輝く点と点が夜空で
Shining points and points in the night sky
降る五線譜 描く星座
Falling musical staves drawing constellations
あたし今 最上級に可愛いの!
I'm currently at my absolute cutest!
君に振られて 最上級に可愛いの!
Dumped by you, I became at my absolute cutest!
これが乙女の逆襲だ!
This is a maiden's counterattack!
もう気づいているかも知れないけど言うわ
You might have already noticed, but I'll say it
あたしね 今とても 可愛い
I am very cute right now
君がはじめた恋 君が終わらせるなんて
The romance you started, you ending it
なんだそれ 泣いちゃうぞ かわいい
What's with that, I'm gonna cry, cute
あたしの夢中くだけ散険
My engrossed and shattered obsession
友達から聞いたよ
I heard from a friend
恋敵多すぎて失恋直後は
A rival in love, immediately after heartbreak
涙でぐちゃぐちゃでかわいい
Messy with tears and cute
君が残したのに 雑なサヨナラだった
Even though you left behind a sloppy goodbye
君に振られて 最上級に可愛いの!
Dumped by you, I became at my absolute cutest!
認めなよ これが乙女の逆襲だ!
Admit it, this is a maiden's counterattack!
むしろありがとう 最上級に可愛くなったって
Rather, thank you, I became at my absolute cutest!
言って知って あいつがなんか可愛くなったって
Saying and knowing that guy became somewhat cute
君に振られて 最上級に可愛いの!
Dumped by you, I became at my absolute cutest!
自分史上一番ときめき放つわ
Exuding the most heartthrobs in my personal history
最上級に可愛いの! 認めなよ!
At my absolute cutest! Admit it!
これが乙女の逆襲だ!
This is a maiden's counterattack!
君に振られて 最上級に可愛いの!
Dumped by you, I became at my absolute cutest!
最上級に可愛いの! 認めなよ!
At my absolute cutest! Admit it!
これが乙女の逆襲だ!
This is a maiden's counterattack!
君に振られて 最上級に可愛くなりました
Dumped by you, I became at my absolute cutest!
むしろありがとう 最上級に可愛くなったって
Rather, thank you, I became at my absolute cutest!
言って知って あいつがなんか可愛くなったって
Saying and knowing that guy became somewhat cute
君に振られて 最上級に可愛いの!
Dumped by you, I became at my absolute cutest!
自分史上一番ときめき放つわ
Exuding the most heartthrobs in my personal history
最上級に可愛いの! 認めなよ!
At my absolute cutest! Admit it!
これが乙女の逆襲だ!
This is a maiden's counterattack!
君に振られて 最上級に可愛いの!
Dumped by you, I became at my absolute cutest!
最上級に可愛いの! 認めなよ!
At my absolute cutest! Admit it!
これが乙女の逆襲だ!
This is a maiden's counterattack!
まあ一応一緒にまった歌いたいー、まにあいそ
Well, together, well, we wanted to sing...
みたいな感じで、お届けいただいたの、どう、先ほどお聞きいただいた
Like that, we were able to deliver it, I wonder how?
え、最初級に可愛いの！
Well, first off, so cute!
このね、おなじみの、あんまからっぺでいいのかな？
This, you know, as usual... is it okay to be a little bare-bellied?
おなじみのメンバーでね、
With our familiar members, you know...
このNIKKEのこのステージで、ちょっと可愛く歌わせていただきましたよ、どうでしたかー？
We were able to sing this NIKKE stage so cutely, how was it?
すごい、最初、なんか「うーん」って、
It was really like, "Ooh," right?
みんながね、「うーん」って上がってくる、あのね、演奏をさせていただきました。
Everyone went "Ooh," raising their voices!
可愛い、ありがとうね、みんな歌ってくれて、ありがとうー！
Cute, thank you everyone, for singing along, thank you!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you!
ということでですね、こちらまだ嬉しいお知らせ残っております！
So, you see, we still have happy announcements left!
はい、え、ここからはですね、告知をさせていただこうかなと、あまやましわー！
Yes, from here we will make an announcement about Nakiri Ayame's...
え、なんとなくね、みんなちょっとお気づきなんじゃないかなと、
Maybe everyone has noticed by now?
思いつつも！今年も、え、なきりあやめ、え、誕生日記念グッズ発売されまーす！やったー！
Thinking about it, this year too, Nakiri Ayame's birthday merchandise is finally going on sale! Yay!
やったー！イエーイ！イエーイイエーイイエーイイエーイ！
Yay! Yay, yay, yay, yay!
まあ最後まで、ちょっと最後まで見ててくださいね、ちょっと最後まで見ててねー！
Well, please watch until the very end, please watch until the very end, okay?
はい！ということでですね、え、今回こちらの商品と、なっておりまーす！どーん！わーめっちゃかわいい！
So, this time, it's packed with these goods! Bam!
え、今回ももりだくさんと、なっているんですけども、
This time too, it's packed full, but...
え、今回のイラストは、え、Tiv先生に、え、描き下ろし、さ、描き下ろしして、いただきました！ありがとうございます！めっちゃ可愛い、可愛いよ、ありがとうございます！
This time's illustration was drawn by Tiv-sensei, thank you so much, it's super cute, cute! Thank you!
じゃあね、ちょっと詳しい詳細を見ていきましょう！
Well, let's take a look at the details, shall we?
まずは、こちら！
First is this!
ホログラムアクリルパネルー！やったー！
Hologram Acrylic Panel! Yay!
え、これめっちゃ可愛いですよね、これ！キラキラしてるんです、これ。可愛い、可愛い、可愛いね！
Oh, this is super cute, right? It's sparkling, cute, cute!
え、こちらですね、え、1周年、の、ライブをちょっとね、テーマにした、テーマに合わせたパレードっぽい感じの、え、アクリルパネルと、なっておりまーす！可愛いよー！
And this is, like, a parade-like feel matching the theme of the 3D live, an acrylic panel! Cute!
あ、キラキラしてて可愛いね！
It's glittering and cute, right?
はい！え、続きまして、こちら！ぬいぐるみキーホルダー、巫女衣装ver.！やったー！
Yes, next is this! Plushie Keychain Miko Outfit Ver.! Yay!
ぬいぐるみのキーホルダーを、グッズとして、よのグッズとして出すの、多分初めてなんですけど、一応今回はね、あのー
Releasing a plushie keychain as goods is, I think, a first for us, but this time...
巫女衣装の、あの小さい、このね、これぐらいかな、ぬいぐるみのキーホルダーを、え、作らせていただきましたー！
We made a small, miko-outfit-wearing plushie keychain, about this size!
このね、あの、ぜひ、あのいろんなとこつけて、あの、連れてってくださーい！お出かけしやすいね、サイズ感となっておりますので、一緒に連れてってねー！
Please take it with you to all sorts of places, it's easy to take out and is a nice size, so please take it along with you!
はい！え、続きまして、こちら！百鬼組ボディバッグ！
Yes, next is this! Nakiri Gumi Body Bag!
やったー！ちょっとね、さりげなく、なんかよ、よ推しですよっていうアピールできるような、デザインにさせていただきました！
Yay! It has a design where you can subtly appeal your Nakiri Gumi status.
ちょっとなんか、このバッグにお出かけキーホルダーやらをつけちゃって、一緒にお出かけ連れてってもらえたらな、嬉しいなって感じです！はい！
If you attach the keychain to the bag and take us out together, I'd be so happy! Yes.
と、いうことでですね、続きまして、こちら！ぽよよフード付きタオルー！
And next is this! Poyoyo Hooded Towel!
こちらね、イベントなんやらでもかぶって、百鬼組ですよっていうアピールできちゃう、商品と、なっておりまーす！
This is a product where you can appeal that you're part of Nakiri Gumi by wearing it at events and stuff!
みんなもね、ぽよよになれちゃいますよ、こうやって。かぶってね、真っ白になってください！
Everyone, become poyoyo and turn pure white, okay?
はい、なんかね、ぜひいろんな、あのグッズもね、ライブとして、こう、いろんな参戦グッズとして使えるかなというラインナップになっております！
Yes, please use various goods as live goods, as participation goods!
え、続きましてですね、続きまして、こちら！シチュエーションボイス「遊園地デート」！
Yes, next is this! Situation Voice "Amusement Park Date"!
今回は、え、ちょっと描き下ろしイラストに合わせた遊園地をテーマにしたボイスと、なっております。あの、一部ね、ちょっと紹介させていただいたグッズも、ちょっとストーリーにも、ちょっと出てくるので、こちらも楽しみに聞いていただければと思います！よろしくお願いします！
This is a voice pack themed around an amusement park date that matches the illustration, and since some of the goods we introduced earlier also tie into the story, I hope you'll enjoy listening to it! Thank you for your support!
そして、フルセット購入特典もありまーす！こちら！
And there are also purchase bonuses for the full set! Here!
え、数量限定版は、え、直筆サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードと、誕生日記念フルセットは、箔押し複製サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードと、誕生日ディナーデートのASMRボイスが、ついてきまーす！ちょっと恥ずかしいですね！
The quantity-limited version includes a foil-signed bromide card with a cheki-style design, and the regular version includes a printed-signature bromide card with a cheki-style design, plus an ASMR voice "Birthday Dinner Date"!
え、でもこれね、ブロマイドカードも可愛いですね！
Well, the bromide card is also cute.
え、そしてですね、こちらが、なくなり次第、え、箔押し複製サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードと、え、誕生日ディナーデートのASMRボイスと、なっておりますね。あの、頑張って書くので、是非皆さんゲットしてください、よろしくおねがいします！
And this will feature a printed signature, so please get it, everyone! I beg you!
え、他にもですね、なんかの、今年の9月から発売された、あのホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使えるカードがですね、フルセット購入特典として、1枚付いてくるみたいです！
And additionally, as a full-set purchase bonus, it looks like one hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME PR card "Nakiri Ayame" will be included!
ぜひゲットしてくださいね！
Please check it out!
改めてフルセットは、こちらとなります！え、誕生日記念フルセット、よろしくお願いしまーす！え、ちょっとぜひフルセットで買って、あの、ライブやらいろんなお出かけにやら、連れてってくれたら、まあ嬉しいなと思います！
To reiterate, the full set consists of these items! Please look forward to the Nakiri Ayame Birthday Celebration Full Set!
はーい、ということで以上！え、なきりあやめ、誕生日記念2024
Yes, so that's all for the Nakiri Ayame Birthday Celebration 2024!
の、グッズ情報でしたー！
That was the goods info!
みんな、よろしくお願いします！
Thank you all so much!
みんないろんなところに連れてってねー！
Take me along with you to all sorts of places!
はーい、ということで今回
Right, so this time...
総勢…じゃなくて15名のゲストに来ていただいて
...wait, not a grand total—15 guests have come to join us,
こんなね、すごい素敵なステージで
on this amazing, wonderful stage,
いろんなギミックやらをね、新しい挑戦を試みながら
trying out various gimmicks and taking on new challenges,
7回目の誕生日を迎えられて
and celebrating my 7th birthday—
本当幸せです！本当ありがとうございます！
I'm so happy! Thank you all so much!
みんな、たくさん見てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you everyone for watching so much!
このあとですね、21時15分から命限のアンコールライブがちょっとだけあるので
After this, at 9:15 PM, there'll be a short encore live for Inochigurui,
よかったらそちらも見ていてくれたら嬉しいなと思います。
so I'd be so happy if you could check that out too.
みんな本当にありがとね！アンコールライブで終わりましょう！
Thank you all so much! Let's finish up with the encore live!
エンドロールも後から出るからね！バイバーイ！
The ending credits will come up afterwards too! Bye-bye!